Guide to the Charlotte Taft papers, 1977-1999 RL.11590
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charlotte Taft papers
1977-1999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11590
1 Linear Feet
Charlotte Taft is an abortion counselor and activist. Her papers contain clippings and articles documenting various aspects of the struggle for abortion rights as well as brochures from abortion clinics.
Biographical / Historical
Charlotte Taft is a reproductive choice counselor and activist who holds a Master's Degree in Social Psychology. She was also the director of an abortion clinic in Dallas, TX for 17 years and is a former director of The Abortion Care Network.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Charlotte Taft papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Collection Overview
The Charlotte Taft papers contain materials documenting her history as an abortion care counselor and activist. The collection chiefly consists of collected newspaper clippings and articles documenting struggles for various aspects of reproductive justice. It also contains brochures from women's healh care and abortion providers.
- Accession (2017-0212)
  - Clinic brochures, 1977-1987; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Doctor murders, 1993-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clinic harassment, 1978-2004; 3 folders (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Clinic programs and providers, 1993-2003; 4 folders (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
  - State regulations, 1993-2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Status of abortion, 1993-2005 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Legal battles, 1994-2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Letters to the editor, 1977-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Clinic investigations and patient deaths, 1993-2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)